What is the rate of growth, the rate of growth at which the running time increases as a function of
input is called rate of growth?
Let us assume that we go to a shop to buy a car and bicycle.
If your friend sees you there and asks what you are buying, then in general, you say buying a car.
This is because the cost of the car is high or high higher than the bicycle.
So the cost of the car is high compared to the cost of bicycle, approximating the cost of that bicycle
to the cost of the car.
So the total cost the car price would be like $40000 and the price of bicycle is $100.
So the total cost for you and for your friend or or whatever it would be the total cost equal to the
price of the car.
OK.
So we neglect the price of bicycle.
Similarly, in the computer engineering or computer science for the ABI of this mentioning the mentioned
example, we can represent the cost of a car and the cost of bicycle in terms of function.
And for a given function, ignore the low or there are terms that we are a relatively insignificant
for large value of input size.
And so consider and it's and power for glass 100 and squared plus four is approximately equal to and
to power forward as an example in the case in this case and to power forward and squared and and power
zero are the individual costs of some function and approximate to end to power for since, and the power
four is the highest rate of growth.
OK, so.
Let's see the rate of growth in algorithms in the same example of the car and the bicycle.
We have the big own notation that we are going to learn in the next video.
And these are the examples of algorithms.
So we are going to go deeply in the next videos for the big old notation.
And we take an example about them.
But till now, I need from you to understand that the highest power in that function would be considered
as its the biggest rate of growth.
OK, so.
We will start from or to do one.
OK.
One.
This is pushing our pink or in queue or deck, accessing an array element.
It will cost us one.
OK, look to look of and in like in binary search of an linear search, search and and look and hips
or earthquakes or merge thought and a square selection sort insertions or bubble sword and to power
three matrix multiplication and dude power and towers of A..
Don't worry, we will clarify everything and the next soap I need from you to understand the rate of
growth, growth and in this way, so we take the highest degree and the.